To use Tessle with your projects, just
run Tessle in it in the project
directory. To create a spec for
something like say an MCP server in this
case, I'll just ask my agent to do it
with Tessle. The agent will optionally
gather some additional information from
me as appropriate and then use Tessle's
create tool to generate a spec file.
Tessle created specs are markdown files
with some specific conventions such as
generates links that indicate exactly
what code this spec represents, optional
API blocks which we ensure are
implemented in your code, integrations
with tests that are matched to specific
behaviors, and explicit control over
your code's dependencies. Now, with the
spec, I can ask my agent to generate
code with Tessle's build tool. All of
Tesla's MCP tools like build and create
are optimized for specific tasks and
keep your overall agent session more
productive. Specs make it really easy to
engage with your project's behavior with
what the agent builds without getting
bogged down in how the agent does it.
Now, if you already have existing code,
you can use our document tool to
generate a spec from it. The resulting
spec acts as documentation for this code
and you can use it to evolve your code
moving forward by changing the describes
link to a generates link and using the
Tessle build tool we saw earlier. Now
once you've iterated on your spec and
code and gotten something you like, you
can add tests to your spec using
Tessle's build test tool. The tests are
nicely integrated with your spec so you
can easily see how they relate to
specified behaviors and they act as
regression protection for future agent
sessions. Now Tessle guides your agent
to create a plan before acting to save
them in a dedicated folder and to update
them as it makes progress. This improves
consistency and creates a clear audit
trail and encourages you and your agent
to work incrementally regularly giving
each other feedback. Now, let's talk
about Tesla's spec registry. When using
thirdparty code, agents often struggle
getting it right, hallucinating
non-existent APIs, mixing up versions,
and often just getting stuck. Tesla spec
registry is full of versioned agent
optimized documentation for thousands of
open source libraries which helps agents
use these libraries faster and more
effectively. It's a much better
alternative to watching your agent go
through countless iterations trying to
get it right. You can search for and
install these explicitly using the
Tessle CLI or you can just ask your
agent to find and install whatever specs
you need. The usage specs are
distributed as packages that match the
versions of the code they describe so
agents always have the right guidance
within easy reach. Well, that's a quick
tour of the Tesla framework and the spec
registry designed to keep your coding
agents productive and on the rails. The
spec registry is available for free for
anyone to use today. Try it out now with
your favorite agents. And for the Tessle
framework, we're rolling out access over
the coming weeks and you can request
your spot on our website. To learn more,
please check out our docs at
docs.tesle.io.
And thanks for watching.